For video [https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yxy1BOC1-q8]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
- ROB DODSON: 嗨  大家好
ROB DODSON: Hey, everybody.
怎么回事呢
What's up?
我是 Rob Dodson
It's Rob Dodson.
我们再一次来到 Progressive Web apps 峰会
We are here again at the Progressive Web Apps Summit.
我们现在在演讲者等候室
We are in the speaker ready room.
这里是演讲者交换的地方
This is where folks are hanging out in between their talks.
我刚刚和 Alex Russell 在聊天
I'm joined right now with Alex Russell, who is a software
他是 Chrome 团队的软件工程师
engineer on the Chrome team.
Alex 可以说是 progressive web apps 的鼻祖了
Alex is sort of like the progenitor of progressive web apps.
我这么说对吗
Did I use that word correctly?
- ALEX RUSSELL: 是的
ALEX RUSSELL: Yeah.
- ROB DODSON: 好
ROB DODSON: OK.
感觉不错
That felt good.
作为 progressive web apps 的
Sort of like a creator of some of the concepts
一些相关概念的创造者
around progressive web apps.
我比较好奇  Alex
And I'm curious, Alex, for someone
对于一些不熟悉 progressive web apps 的人来说
who is new to the topic of progressive web apps,
你是否可以和我们简单介绍下
can you tell us a little bit about what
这些概念意味着什么？
it means for something to be one of these things?
这是一个混合应用吗  还是其他什么
Is this like a hybrid app, or what is this exactly?
- ALEX RUSSELL: 好的
ALEX RUSSELL: Yeah.
这和混合应用不一样
So unlike hybrid apps, which you kind of package up and put
混合应用可能需要你打包  整合  发布到商店
in a bundle and then distribute through a store,
而 progressive web apps 仅仅是网站
progressive web apps are just websites.
如果你使用它们的次数足够多
Except if you use them enough and if they
以及它们满足特定的质量标准
meet specific quality criteria so that the browser knows
那么浏览器会觉得它运行良好 然后说下线
that it would work well, say offline, or had
或者已经获得良好的主页数据
good metadata for your home screen, once it meets that bar,
一旦满足条件  浏览器开始把它看做一个应用
the browser can start to treat that more like an app,
同时  你可以开始选择拥有它
and you can start to opt in to having it or keeping it
或者把它保存在主页  把它放到应用列表诸如此类。
to your home screen, putting it in your apps list, that sort of thing.
那么  如果我是一个商家
ROB DODSON: And so if I'm a business
我正在了解这个  对我来说有什么吸引人的使用场景呢
and I'm checking this out, what is the motivating use case
好吧  比如说
for me to be like, all right, cool,
如何把我们当前的东西转换为这个模式呢
let's take our current thing and switch over to this model?
这种模式有一堆的底层技术
ALEX RUSSELL: So the model has a bunch of underlying tech below it.
你需要得到 TLS ( Transport Layer Security )
So you need to get TLS.
你要有一个安全的网站
You have to have a secure site.
Service workers 会提供离线
Service workers are what enable offline and reliable
可靠的性能  消息推送
performance, and push notifications,
以及许多其他优秀的现代 web 东西
and a bunch of other really good modern web stuff.
一旦你拥有了这些  并把它们整合起来
And once you have all of that, and you put it all together,
仅仅通过一条连接
you can deliver an experience to users
用户就可以得到和原生的应用相媲美的体验
just through a link that can rival native apps.
最后  他们可以存在于主页
And eventually, they can be on the home screen
并重新参与  就像是一个原生的应用。
and be reengaging just like native apps.
这个真的有效
And it's really working.
正在着手构建 progressive web apps 的人们
The folks who are starting to build progressive web
甚至没有支持 progressive web apps 的浏览器厂商
apps, even for browsers that don't support them,
他们都看到重大的前景
are seeing major gains.
像 Ali Express  一支相当强大的团队
Like Ali Express, really strong team.
他们似乎停止其他运作
They just sort of stopped the world,
把网站转为了 progressive web apps
and they turned their site into a progressive web app.
他们甚至在 iOS 中也看到很大的提升
And they saw a huge lift in engagement, even on iOS.
移动互联网体验领域的投资
So really investing in the mobile web experience
仍然在探索中
is what this is about.
但是  我们能让你
But we give you the ability to actually get
真的获得 Android 上的类应用体验
to app-like experiences on Android.
- ROB DODSON: 好吧  我被说服了
ROB DODSON: And so, OK, I'm sold.
我开始想做这件事
I want to start doing this.
有哪些工具
What are some tools that I can use
我可以用来转换到这个模式吗
to start to transition over to this model?
这是很大的技术进步
ALEX RUSSELL: It's a big tech step.
但是  可以确认的是  对现在的人们来说
But the hardest part so far for folks
最难的部分是你要满足参与的门槛
has been verifying that you meet that engagement bar,
门槛是指你的应用质量
that quality bar for your app.
现在有一些工具能起到帮助
And there's a couple of tools that are helping now.
你可以在 Chrome Canary 测试版下
If you check out the new Applications
开发者工具里的新应用面板
Panel in Dev Tools in Canary in beta in Chrome,
找到一堆的支持帮助
you'll see that there's a bunch of support
在调试应用时
for getting all the information you need about your app
你便能得到所需要的全部信息
when you're doing live debugging.
同时  在 Google 的 github 下面
And also there's a project called
有个名为 Lighthouse 的项目
Lighthouse, which is in the Google Chrome organization on GitHub.
这个项目很棒
And this is awesome because it gives you
它提供拓展和命令行的工具
an extension and a command line tool that you can verify
它可以用来验证你是否满足所有的标准条件
that you've met all those criteria with, which is pretty awesome.
这帮我省下了大量的时间
Saved me tons of time.
推荐一下
Recommended.
- ROB DODSON: 好了
ROB DODSON: Right on.
我们会在节目笔记中
So we will include links to all the tools
包含 Alex 推荐的所有工具的链接
that Alex mentioned down in the show notes.
在 YouTube 的 Chrome 开发者频道
We've also got links to Alex's talk
我们也会提供  Alex 演讲的链接
on the Chrome Developers YouTube channel down there as well.
Alex  在晴朗的 Amsterdam 非常感谢你和我们在一起
Alex, thank you so much for being with us today in sunny Amsterdam.
我是来自 PWA (Progressive Web App) 峰会的 Rob Dodson
I'm Rob Dodson from the PWA Summit.
我们下次见
I'll see you around.
[MUSIC PLAYING]